Hi, I'm Diana and I'm a partner at YC.
大家好，我是戴安娜，我是 YC 的合夥人。
Over the past few months, it's become
在過去的幾個月裡，我越來越
clear to me that AI is not just going to
清楚地意識到，人工智慧不僅會
change how quickly software gets built
改變軟體的開發速度
or what workflows get automated. It's
或自動化的工作流程。它將從
going to fundamentally change the way
根本上改變新
startup should be run from what roles
創公司的運作方式，從公司需要扮演哪些角色
will exist to what products are possible
到可以開發哪些產品
to build. In this episode, I'm going to
。在這一集中，我將
discuss how founders should think about
討論創辦人應該如何思考
building an AI native company, what
打造一家人工智慧原生公司，
roles their team should have, and what
他們的團隊應該有哪些角色，以及
concrete internal practices they can
他們現在可以採取哪些具體的內部實踐來
adopt right now to move much faster.
更快地前進。
Currently, most people talk about AI in
目前，大多數人談論人工智慧都是從
terms of productivity. They'll talk at
生產力的角度出發。他們會詳細討論
length about how it can make engineers
如何提高工程師的工作
more productive or say we need to add
效率，或者說我們需要將
copilot to existing workflows and ship
Copilot 加入現有的工作流程中，並發布
more features. This framing misses the
更多功能。這種框架忽略了
shift we're currently seeing, which is
我們目前正在看到的轉變，而這種轉變與其說是
less about productivity boosts than
生產力的提高，不如說是
entirely new capabilities. The right
全新的能力的出現。
person with AI tools can now build
現在，只要擁有合適的AI工具，就能建立出以前
features that used to require an entire
需要整個
team or were just impossible. Thinking
團隊才能完成甚至根本無法實現的功能。從新
about AI in terms of new capabilities
功能的角度思考人工智慧，對
founders should run their companies. At
創辦人如何經營公司有許多啟示。從
a high level, the way to think about AI
宏觀層面來看，看待人工智慧的方式應該
is that it should not be a tool your
是，它不應該
company just uses. It should be the
只是公司使用的工具。它應該是貴
operating system your company runs on.
公司使用的作業系統。
Every workflow, every decision and every
每個工作流程、每個決策和每個
process should flow through an
流程都應該透過一個
intelligent layer that is constantly
不斷
learning and improving. What this means
學習和改進的智慧層來處理。具體來說，這意味著公司
concretely is every important process in
裡的每個重要流程都
your company should be captured by an
應該被一個
intelligent close loop. A close loop
智慧閉環系統所捕捉。閉環系統
captures information, feeds it back into
捕獲訊息，將其反饋到
an intelligent systems, and improves the
智慧系統中，並
process over time. If you've ever
隨著時間的推移改進流程。如果你
studied control systems, you'll be
學過控制系統，你就會
familiar with the difference between an
熟悉
open loop and a closed loop system. Open
開環系統和閉環系統的差異。開
loops are controlled systems without
環控制系統是指沒有
feedback loops. In the old world,
回授迴路的控制系統。在舊世界，
companies basically ran as open loops.
公司基本上是以開放式循環的方式運作的。
You made a decision, executed it, and
你做出了決定，執行了決定，但並
didn't always systematically measure the
沒有總是系統地衡量
outcome and adjust the process. Open
結果並調整過程。開環
loops are inherently lossy. A closed
電路本質上是有損耗的。
loop, on the other hand, is
另一方面，閉環系統具有
self-regulating. It continuously
自我調節能力。它不斷
monitors its output and adjusts its
監控其產出，並調整其
process to better meet the stated goal.
流程以更好地實現既定目標。
Closed loops are extremely powerful for
閉環系統對於
correctness and stability. With
正確性和穩定性來說非常強大。有了能夠
self-improving agents, your company
自我提升的代理人，你的公司
should run as a closed loop. To build
就能像一個閉環系統一樣運作。要建立
these closed loops, you will need to
這些閉環，你需要
make your entire company queryable. In
讓整個公司都可查詢。
other words, the whole organization
換句話說，整個組織都
should be legible to AI. Every important
應該對人工智慧可讀。每項重要
action should produce an artifact that
措施都應該產生可供公司
the intelligence at the center of the
核心智慧團隊
company can learn from and use to
學習並用於
self-improve. This means recording your
自我改進的成果。這意味著要使用
meetings with the AI notetaker,
AI 筆記者記錄會議內容，
minimizing DMs and emails, and embedding
盡量減少私訊和電子郵件，並
agents throughout communication of all
在所有管道的溝通中嵌入代理商
channels. It also means building custom
。這也意味著要建立
dashboards with everything in the
包含公司所有資訊的自訂儀表板，包括
company, revenue, sales, engineering,
收入、銷售、工程、
hiring, ops, everything. Here's a
招聘、營運等等。以下是一個
concrete example of how it could work.
具體的例子，說明它是如何運作的。
Take engineering, management, and sprint
以工程、管理和迭代
planning. If you have an agent that has
計劃為例。如果你的代理人可以
access to your linear tickets, all your
存取你的線性工單、所有
Slack engineering channels, all customer
Slack 工程頻道、所有
feedback from emails or tools like Pylon
來自電子郵件或 Pylon 和 GitHub 等工具的客戶回饋、
and GitHub, highle plans in a notion or
Notion 或 Google 文件中的高級計劃
Google doc, sales calls and recordings
、銷售電話和
from daily standups, then the agent can
每日站會錄音，那麼該代理人就可以
analyze what was actually shipped in
分析你在上一個迭代中實際交付了什麼，
your previous sprint and how well they
以及它們在多大程度上
met customers needs for real. From
滿足了客戶的需求。從
there, you can go a step further with
那裡，您可以更進一步，
full visibility into what shipped, what
全面了解哪些產品已出貨、哪些產品有效
worked, and what didn't. Agents can
、哪些產品無效。經紀人可以
start looking ahead. They can propose
開始展望未來了。他們可以
sprint plans for engineers that are way
為工程師制定更可預測、
more predictable and accurate and on
更準確、更符合
track. The days of anch manager status
進度的衝刺計畫。
rollups that are super lossy are gone.
那種損耗極大的錨點管理器狀態匯總的時代已經過去了。  我
Having managed engineering teams myself
曾親自管理過工程團隊，
and now seeing this across multiple YC
現在在多家 YC 公司也看到了這種情況
companies, this is a gamecher. What used
，這真是個棘手的問題。過去
to require constant coordination becomes
需要不斷協調的事情，現在預設變得
legible and querable by default. I've
清晰易懂，可以查詢。我
seen teams that do this cut their
見過一些團隊這樣做，將
engineering sprint time in half and get
工程衝刺時間縮短了一半，並在
close to 10x more done in that time. The
相同的時間內完成了近 10 倍的工作量。
overarching principle here is that to
這裡最重要的原則是，要
get their full capabilities, you need to
充分發揮模型的能力，你需要像對待員工一樣，為
provide models with as much context as
模型提供盡可能多的背景資訊
you would provide an employee. When you
。這樣
do this, your company stops operating as
做，你的公司就不再像以前那樣以
a open loop where information is
開放式循環的方式運作，資訊不再是
fragmented and manually interpreted. It
分散的，也不再需要人工解讀。它就
becomes instead a closed loop system.
變成了一個閉環系統。
Status, decisions, and outcomes are
狀態、決策和結果會
continuously captured and fed back into
持續捕捉並回饋到
this intelligence layer. The result is a
這個智慧層。最終得到的
system that always has an upto-date view
系統能夠始終掌握最新
of what's actually happening. There's
實際情況。此外，
highest velocity companies build product
高速發展的公司建構產品
AI software factories. If you're
人工智慧軟體工廠的方式也正在形成一種新的典範。如果你
familiar with the testdriven development
熟悉測試驅動開發（
or TDD, this is the next evolution of
TDD），那麼這就是它的下一個發展階段
that. With software factories, humans
。在軟體工廠中，人類
write a spec and a set of tests that
編寫規格和一組
define success and then AI agents
定義成功的測試，然後人工智慧代理
generate the implementation
產生實作
and code and iterate until the test
和程式碼，並不斷迭代，直到測試
pass. The human defines what to build
通過。人決定要建造什麼，
and judges the output. The actual code
並評判最終成果。實際編寫程式碼
is the agent's job. Some companies have
是代理的工作。有些公司
already pushed this to the point where
已經將這種理念推向了極致，
their repos contain no handwritten code,
他們的程式碼庫中不再包含任何手寫程式碼，
just specs and test harnesses. Strong
只有規範和測試框架。 Strong
DM's AI team is an example of how to do
DM 的 AI 團隊就是如何做到這一點的一個例子
this. Their end goal was a system that
。他們的最終目標是建立一個從根本上
essentially eliminated the need for a
消除
human to write or review code. And so
人工編寫或審查程式碼需求的系統。因此，
they built their own software factory
他們建立了自己的軟體工廠，
where specs and a scenario based
其中規範和基於場景的
validations drive agents to write tests
驗證驅動代理人編寫測試
and iterate on code until it meets a
並迭代程式碼，直到程式碼達到
probabilistic satisfaction threshold and
機率滿意度閾值並能夠正常
it works. This is how you achieve the
運作。這就是
thousandx engineer that Steve Jay talks
史蒂夫傑伊所說的「千倍工程師」的實現方法：
about by surrounding a single engineer
圍繞單一工程師
with a system of agents that enable them
建立一個代理系統，使他能夠
to build things they would have never
建立
been able to build before. The era of
以前從未建造過的東西。擁有
the thousand or even 10,000 X engineer
成千上萬甚至上萬名X工程師的時代已經
is here. One implication of building
來臨。以
your company this way with AI loops
這種方式建立公司，
everywhere, a queryable organization and
到處都是人工智慧循環、可查詢的組織和
software factories is that the classic
軟體工廠，這意味著傳統的
management hierarchy no longer makes
管理層級結構不再有意義
sense. In the old world, you needed
。在舊世界，你需要
middle managers and coordinators to
中階管理人員和協調員來
route information inefficiently up and
低效地在組織內部上下傳遞訊息
down an organization. In the new world,
。在新世界裡，
the intelligence layer serves that
智慧層發揮這樣的
purpose. If your company is queryable,
作用。如果你的公司對人工智慧來說可查詢、資訊
artifactrich, and legible to an AI, you
豐富且易於理解，那麼你
should have almost no human middleware.
幾乎不需要任何人工中間件。
This matters because your company's
這很重要，因為公司的發展
velocities is only as fast as its
速度取決於其
information flow. Every layer of human
資訊流動的速度。每減少一層人為
routing you can remove is the direct
路由，
speed gain. A great example is what Jack
速度就能直接提升。傑克·多西在 Block 所做的事情就是一個很好的例子
Dorsey is doing over at Block. After
。在
going deep on the tools, he's come to
深入研究了各種工具之後，他得出了與
the same conclusion many have. This is
許多人相同的結論。這
about more than just incremental
不僅僅是關於
productivity gains. His view is that if
生產力的逐步提高。他認為，如果
you keep the same org chart and
保留同樣的組織架構和
management structure, you've missed the
管理結構，就
shift entirely. The company itself has
完全錯過了改變的機會。公司本身
to be rebuilt as an intelligence layer
必須進行重建，成為一個
with humans at the edge guiding it
由人類在邊緣引導的智慧層，而
rather than routing information through
不是僅僅透過它來路由資訊
it. Going forward, Jack suggests every
。傑克認為，未來每家
company will have three employee
公司都會有三種員工
archetypes. The first is the individual
類型。第一種是個人
contributor or IC basically the builder
貢獻者或 IC，基本上是建造者/
operator. This is someone who directly
運營者。這是
makes and runs things in an AI native
在一家人工智慧原生公司中直接負責產品開發和營運的人
company. This is not limited to
。這不僅限於
engineers. Everyone builds and ops
工程師。每個人都參與產品開發，營運
support sales. Everyone comes to
支援銷售。大家來
meetings with working prototypes not
開會都帶著工作原型，而不是
pitch decks. Second is the DRRI the
簡報。其次是 DRRI，即
directly responsible individual focused
直接負責的個人，專注
on strategy and customer outcomes. This
於策略和客戶成果。這
is not a classic manager is the person
不是傳統意義上的經理，經理是
with a clear responsibility for the
對結果負有明確責任的人
result. One person, one outcome, no
。一人一果，無處
hiding. The third is the AI founder
遁形。第三種類型是人工智慧創辦人
type. This person still builds, still
。這個人仍然在建設，仍然在
coaches and leads by example. If you're
指導，並且以身作則。如果你是
the founder, this needs to be you at the
創辦人，那麼你必須衝在最
forefront, showing your team what
前線，向你的團隊展示
massive capability gains look like, not
能力大幅提升是什麼樣子，而不是將
delegating your AI strategy to someone
你的人工智慧策略委託給
else. With this structure, companies
其他人。借助這種架構，公司
will be able to get outsized results
可以用規模
with much smaller teams. Maximizing
小得多的團隊獲得巨大的成果。關鍵在於最大限度地
token usage, not headcount, will be the
利用代幣，而不是增加人員數量
critical shift. The best companies will
。最好的公司將
be the ones that are token maxing. Think
是那些代幣發行量達到上限的公司。
of the trade-off this way. One person
這樣想，權衡利弊就好。一個
with AI tools can be the equivalent of
擁有人工智慧工具的人就能完成以前人工智慧出現之前
what used to take a large engineering
一個大型工程
team at a preAI company. That means
團隊才能完成的工作。這意味著
dramatically leaner engineering, design,
工程、設計、
HR, and admin teams. And so you should
人力資源和行政團隊需要大幅精簡。因此，你應該
be willing to run an uncomfortably high
願意承擔高昂的
API bill because it's replacing what
API 費用，因為它取代了原本需要
would have taken a far more expensive
更昂貴
and inflated headcount. But don't just
、更龐大的人力才能完成的工作。但不要
take my word for any of this. You cannot
只聽我的一面之詞。你不能
outsource your conviction on the power
把對這些工具力量的信念外包出去
of these tools. You need to develop it
。你需要
yourself by actually sitting with coding
自己動手開發，透過與編碼
agents and using them until you start to
代理一起工作和使用它們，直到你開始
break your own priors about what is now
打破自己對現在可以建立什麼的先入為主。
possible to build. If you are an early
如果你是早期
stage founder, you have a huge advantage
創業者，那麼在這方面你擁有巨大的優勢
in getting ahead on this. You don't have
。果園裡沒有老舊系統，也沒有
of people to retrain. You are small
成千上萬需要重新訓練的人員。你們
enough to build your company right from
公司規模還小，可以從第一天起就把公司發展壯大。但
day one. The opposite is the case for
對於
existing companies. They have to
現有公司而言，情況則恰恰相反。他們必須在
maintain and grow a live product while
維護和發展現有產品的同時，
unwinding years of standard operating
摒棄多年來關於軟體建構方式的標準作業
procedures and core assumptions about
程序和核心假設
how software gets built. Some companies
。有些公司
can achieve this by spinning up small
可以透過組建小型內部研發團隊來實現這一目標，這些團隊可以
AI native systems from scratch separate
從零開始建立獨立於核心業務的人工智慧原生系統
from the core business. Mutiny is a
。叛變就是一個
great example of this. But for most,
很好的例子。但對大多數人來說，
every change to their core processes
核心流程的每一次改變都有
risk breaking something that already
可能破壞已經
works. So by their nature, these large
運作良好的系統。因此，從本質上講，這些大
companies will have a much harder time
公司要實現
going AI native. Startups don't have
人工智慧原生化將會困難得多。新創企業沒有
that constraint and that's a major edge
這種限制，這是一個可以利用的重大優勢。
to take advantage of. You can design
您可以從一開始就圍繞著人工智慧來設計
your systems, workflows and culture
您的系統、工作流程和文化，比現有企業快上
operate thousand times faster than the
千倍。  還是那一套。